a key driver of malignant transformation
tumor maintenance and resistance to
therapy is the impairment of a critical
cellular function a puto --ss or
programmed cell death abt 199 or GDC
zero 199 is a small molecule designed to
selectively bind and inhibit bcl-2 a
critical regulator of a puto psious
bcl-2 is a member of a larger family of
structurally related proteins that are
either pro a photonic or anti a photonic
the dynamic balance between anti a
patata members such as bcl-2 and pro a
patata family members can determine
whether a cell lives or dies by binding
common structures shared among pro a
patata family members bcl-2 inhibits a
puto --ss in response to stress normal
cells as well as certain cancer cells
will up regulate pro a patata family
members in normal cells this increased
expression of pro a patata proteins is
sufficient to induce a puto sious in
contrast malignant cells will often
express more bcl-2 to keep pro a patata
kembers in check this prevents cancer
cells from eliciting and a patata chrous
Ponce
although increased bcl-2 expression
allows the cancer cell to survive under
continual metabolic stress the reserve
of pro a patata family members
sequestered by bcl-2 can leave those
cells vulnerable to cell death
co-developed by AB V and Genentech 199
is an orally available small molecule
designed to selectively bind and inhibit
bcl-2 upon binding bcl-2 199 can
displace the store of pro a patata
proteins in malignant cells this causes
a shift in the dynamic balance between
the available bcl-2
and pro a patata family members inducing
a puto sious with bcl-2 inhibited by
$1.99 pro a patata proteins are left
free to promote poor formation in the
mitochondria signaling a point of no
return
for the cell cytochrome C and other
factors are subsequently released from
the mitochondria initiating the caspase
activation cascade the activation of
these proteolytic enzymes coordinates
the ordered destruction of the cancer
cell app-v and Genentech are continuing
their research into the selective bcl-2
inhibitor ABT 199 or GDC 0 199